Guide to the The New Leader Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
These records consist of correspondence, artwork, subject files, business records, and meeting minutes. The collection also includes the entire print run of the magazine, from 1924 until 2006. It features business letters between editors and contributing authors. Artwork used in The New Leader is organized by subject, or artist. The subject files touch on various topics, including the journal's interactions with other liberal-socialist groups, as well as its contacts with government agencies. Business and administrative records, as well as meeting minutes, detail the inner workings of the publication.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into eight series.
I. Bound Volumes and Issues, 1924-2006
II. Correspondence, 1895-2008
II.1. Correspondence, 1895-1960
II.2. Correspondence, 1939-1958
II.3. Correspondence, 1939-2008
III. Subject Files, 1919-1968
IV. Business Files, 1922-2008
IV.1. Administrative, 1923-1979
IV.2. Editorial, 1944-2008
IV.3. Financial, 1922-1998
V. Artwork, 1928-2006
V.1. Artwork by Subject, 1961-2006
V.2. General Artwork, 1961-1975
V.3. Oversized--Artwork by Subject, 1961-2006
V.4. Oversized--General Artwork and Covers, 1928-1998
V.5. Oversized--Mechanicals, 1961-1994
V.6. Oversized--New York Public Library Exhibit, 1957-1973
VI. Photos, 1906-2005
VI.1. Photographs by Subject, 1924-2005
VI.2. Removed Photographs, 1941-1954
VI.3. Publicity Photographs, 1906-2004
VI.4. Oversized Photographs, 1937-1954
VII. Scrapbooks, 1941-1980
VIII. Ephemera, 1918-1989
Subjects
Bell, Daniel, 1928; Bentley, Eric, 1916-; Geller, Barry, 1932-; Kolatch, Myron.; Kristol, Irving.; Kweskin, Sam.; Levitas, Samuel M.; Lublin, Herb, 1918-1981; Oneal, James, b. 1875.; Victor, Joan Berg.; New York (N.Y.)--Intellectual life.; New York (N.Y.)--Newspapers.; New York County (N.Y.)--Newspapers.; United States--Cultural policy.; United States--Intellectual life--20th century.; Anti-Communism--United States--History.; Arts, American--20th century.; Arts--Political aspects--United States.; Cold War--Social aspects--United States.; Communism.; Freedom and art--Political aspects--United States.; Intellectuals--New York (State)--New York--History--20th century.; Literature--History and criticism--Periodicals.; Political Parties.; Politics and culture--United States.; Socialism--Periodicals.; Socialism--United States.; Socialism--United States--Newspapers.; Socialism--New York (State)--New York--History--20th century.; Genre; Occupation
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions. This collection is located on-site.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
American Labor Conference on International Affairs, Inc Purchase 2006.
Finding aid in repository; folder level control.
- Series I: Bound Volumes and Issues, 1924-2006
  A full run of The New Leader from its first edition in 1924 to its last printed issue in 2006. The collection holds bound volumes for the magazine’s earlier years. After 1950, some volumes are bound, others are loose issues in document boxes.
  - Bound Volume, 1924 (Box 1)
  - Bound Volume, 1925 (Box 2)
  - Bound Volume, 1926 (Box 3)
  - Bound Volume, 1927 (Box 4)
  - Bound Volume, 1928 (Box 5)
  - Bound Volume, 1929 (Box 6)
  - Bound Volume, 1930 (Box 7)
  - Bound Volume, 1931 (Box 8)
  - Bound Volume, 1932 (Box 9)
  - Bound Volume, 1933 (Box 10)
  - Bound Volume, 1934 (Box 11)
  - Bound Volume, 1935 (Box 12)
  - Bound Volume, 1936 (Box 13)
  - Bound Volume, 1937 (Box 14)
  - Bound Volume, 1938 (Box 15)
  - Bound Volume, 1939 (Box 16)
  - Bound Volume, 1940 (Box 17)
  - Bound Volume, 1941 (Box 18)
  - Bound Volume, 1942 (Box 19)
  - Bound Volume, 1943 (Box 20)
  - Bound Volume, 1944 (Box 21)
  - Bound Volume, 1945 (Box 22)
  - Bound Volume, 1946 (Box 23)
  - Bound Volume, 1947 (Box 24)
  - Bound Volume, 1948 (Box 25)
  - Bound Volume, 1949 (Box 26)
  - Bound Volume, 1950 (Box 27)
  - 1951 January-December (Box 47, Folder 1 to 5)
  - 1952 January-March (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - 1952 March-December (Box 48, Folder 1 to 4)
  - 1953 January-August (Box 48, Folder 5 to 7)
  - 1953 August-December (Box 49, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Bound Volume, 1954 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - 1955 January-December (Box 50, Folder 1 to 4)
  - 1956 January-June (Box 50, Folder 5 to 6)
  - 1956 June-December (Box 51, Folder 1 to 3)
  - 1957 January-December (Box 51, Folder 4 to 7)
  - 1958 January-December (Box 52, Folder 1 to 4)
  - Bound Volume, 1959 (Box 28)
  - 1960 January-December (Box 52, Folder 5 to 7)
  - 1961 January-December (Box 53, Folder 1 to 3)
  - 1962 January-December (Box 53, Folder 4 to 5)
  - 1963 January-December (Box 53, Folder 6 to 7)
  - Bound Volume, 1964 (Box 29)
  - Bound Volume, 1965 (Box 30)
  - 1966 January-December (Box 54, Folder 1 to 2)
  - 1967 January-December (Box 54, Folder 3 to 4)
  - Bound Volume, 1968 (Box 31)
  - Bound Volume, 1969 (Box 32)
  - Bound Volume, 1970 (Box 33)
  - Bound Volume, 1971 (Box 34)
  - Bound Volume, 1972 (Box 35)
  - Bound Volume, 1973 (Box 36)
  - Bound Volume, 1974 (Box 37)
  - Bound Volume, 1975 (Box 38)
  - Bound Volume, 1976 (Box 39)
  - Bound Volume, 1977 (Box 40)
  - Bound Volume, 1978 (Box 41)
  - Bound Volume, 1979 (Box 42)
  - Bound Volume, 1980 (Box 43)
  - Bound Volume, 1981 (Box 44)
  - 1982 January-December (Box 54, Folder 5 to 6)
  - 1983 January-March (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - 1983 April-December (Box 55, Folder 1 to 2)
  - 1984 January-December (Box 55, Folder 3 to 4)
  - 1985 January-December (Box 55, Folder 5 to 6)
  - 1986 January-December (Box 55, Folder 7 to 8)
  - 1987 January-December (Box 56, Folder 1 to 3)
  - 1988 January-December (Box 56, Folder 4 to 6)
  - 1989 January-December (Box 56, Folder 7 to 9)
  - 1990 January-December (Box 56, Folder 10 to 11)
  - 1991 January-December (Box 57, Folder 1 to 2)
  - 1992 January-December (Box 57, Folder 3 to 4)
  - 1993 January-December (Box 57, Folder 5 to 6)
  - 1994 January-December (Box 57, Folder 7 to 8)
  - 1995 January-December (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - 1996 January-December (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - 1997 January-December (Box 58, Folder 2 to 4)
  - 1998 January-December (Box 58, Folder 5 to 6)
  - Bound Volume, 1999 (Box 45)
  - 2000 March-December (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - 2001 January-December (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - 2002 January-December (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Bound Volume, 2003 (Box 46)
  - 2004 January-December (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - 2005 January-December (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - 2006 January/April Final Issue (Box 59, Folder 4)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1895, 1934-2008
  The bulk of this series consists of business letters to and from Sol Levitas, executive editor of The New Leader from 1937 to his death in January 1961. The materials in this series are maintained in the organization used by the magazine’s office. There are overlapping years and correspondents. Researchers should be aware of this and must consult all the subseries to ensure they have found all the relevant letters.
  The correspondence is arranged alphabetically. Individual folders are organized reverse chronologically. These letters offer numerous insights into the operations of the magazine. They are mainly devoted to editorial questions, but are also filled with personal exclamations of affection, anxiety over political events, and familiar chit chat. Levitas also had the sad chore of sending condolences to numerous grieving families, as friends of the magazine died over the years.
  - Subseries II.1: Correspondence, 1895, 1934-1960
    This is the bulk of Sol Levitas’ correspondence. Most of it is devoted to business and editorial matters with staff, contributors, printers, and advertisers.
    - A-Ad, 1938-1953 (Box Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Ad-Ald, 1939-1949 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Ald-All, 1941-1954 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Allen, 1942-1951, (5 Folders) (Box 60, Folder 4 to 8)
    - Alt-Ara, 1895, 1943-1952 (Box 60, Folder 9)
      Includes photograph of the St. Petersburg Union for the Emancipation of the Working Class
    - Arc-Axe, 1933-1951 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - B-Bai, 1944-1959 (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Bal, 1943-1954 (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Bal, 1943-1956 (Box Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Ball, 1939-1955 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Bal-Bar, 1946-1959 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Barnes, 1942-1959 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Bar, 1941-1957 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Bau-Baz, 1939-1958 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Bea-Bec 1935-1954 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Bei-Bel, 1943-1957 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Bell, 1942-1948 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Bel-Ber 1942-1957 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Ber, 1942-1958 (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Bes-Bev, 1937-1956 (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - Bid-Bil, 1942-1950 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Bir-Bla, 1939-1952 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Bli-Bod, 1937-1957 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Boh-Bol, 1947-1958 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Bon-Bor, 1939-1959 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Borgese, 1942-1949 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Bor, 1948-1957 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Bor-Bow, 1945-1957 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Boy-Bra, 1942-1956 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Brandt, 1945-1958 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Bra-Bre, 1947-1957 (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Bri-Bro, 1942-1952 (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - Brooks, 1947-1954 (Box 62, Folder 13)
    - Bro, 1944-1958 (Box 62, Folder 14)
    - Brumberg, 1953-1959 (Box 62, Folder 15)
    - Bry-Bud, 1942-1957 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Buell, 1941-1946 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Bullitt, 1941-1953, (2 Folders) (Box 63, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Bun-Bur, 1950-1953 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Bur, 1942-1954 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Bur-Byr, 1943-1957 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Cam-Car, 1944-1958 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Carlson, 1946-1950, (2 Folders) (Box 63, Folder 9 to 10)
    - Car-Cha, 1944-1946 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Chamberlin, 1947-1949, (3 Folders) (Box 63, Folder 12 to 14)
    - Chamberlin, 1941-1946, (5 Folders) (Box 64, Folder 1 to 5)
    - Chapman, 1946-1947 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Cha-Chi, 1943-1958 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Chr, 1954-1958 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Ciccotti, 1952- 1957, (6 Folders) (Box 64, Folder 9 to 14)
    - Cie-Cit 1937-1957 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Cla, 1947-1959 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Cle-Cof, 1954-1959 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Coh-Col, 1948-1953 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Common Cause, 1948 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Corey, 1948-1953 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Cos-Cov, 1954-1958 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Crawford, 1943-1951 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Cro, 1945-1958 (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Cro-Cur, 1939-1957 (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - Dab-Dal, 1943-1947 (Box 65, Folder 11)
    - Dal, 1944-1949 (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - Daniels, 1944-1953, (2 Folders) (Box 66, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Dan-Dav, 1937-1949 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Davis, 1938-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 66, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Dav, 1940-1945 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Del-Dem, 1935-1948 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Den 1941-1948 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Des-Deu, 1939-1948 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Dewey, 1939-1950 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Dew-Dil, 1942-1948 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - Dimitrov, 1946-1950 (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Dim-Don, 1942-1948 (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - Donovan, 1946-1955, (2 Folders) (Box 67, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Dos Passos, 1939-1945 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Dos-Dub, 1940-1947 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Dun-Dyk, 1945-1949 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Eastman, 1939-1945, (2 Folders) (Box 67, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Eat-Edm, 1939-1954 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Her-Eis, 1943-1949 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Elder, 1946-1949 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - Eld-Ell, 1944-1948 (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - Emmet, 1942-1947 (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - Eps-Ern, 1940-1949 (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - Ern-Eze, 1942-1945 (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - Fad-Far, 1939-1958 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Fed-Fei, 1941-1959 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Fei-Fer, 1943-1958 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Fie, 1941-1960 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Fiess, 1943-1952, (3 Folders) (Box 68, Folder 5 to 7)
    - Fis, 1941-1955 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Fitch, 1945-1958, (5 Folders) (Box 68, Folder 9 to 13)
    - Fit-Fos, 1939-1959 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Fos-Fox, 1944-1947 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Frank, 1942-1950 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Fri-Gar, 1942-1952 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Gedye, 1953-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 69, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Ger-Gid, 1939-1945 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Gil-Gla, 1940-1945 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Gliksman, 1956-1958 (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Gol, 1943-1956 (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - Goo-Gra, 1939-1956 (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - Gra-Gre, 1939-1944 (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - Green, 1946-1952 (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - Green, 1936-1945 (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - Gre-Hah, 1939-1959 (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - Hal-Ham, 1939-1957 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Hámori, 1953-1959 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Han-Har, 1942-1959 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Harrison, 1938-1945, (2 Folders) (Box 70, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Har-Has, 1939-1945 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Hat-Hay, 1941-1955 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Hazlitt, 1939-1946 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Hed-Hef, 1942-1950 (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Hei, 1945-1950 (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Heine, 1956-1959 (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Hem--Hen, 1943-1952 (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - Herling, 1935-1959 (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - Her, 1942-1958 (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - Hesseltine, 1943-1956 (Box 70, Folder 15)
    - Hic-Hol, 1938-1959 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Hoo, 1938-1947 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Hop-Hov, 1941-1949 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - How-Hu, 1942-1957 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Hug-Hum, 1942-1948 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Hun-Hur, 1939-1958 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Hurwitz, 1953-1959 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Hym-Jac, 1945-1954 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Jag-Jas, 1938-1957 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Jaszi, 1944-1945 (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Javits, 1949-1954 (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Jeleznov, 1946-1957 (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Jew-Joy, 1941-1954 (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - Kag-Kal, 1941-1945 (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - Kallen, 1939-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 71, Folder 15 to 16)
    - Kal-Kao, 1942-1954 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Kar-Kat, 1942-1948 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Kau-Kaz, 1925-1948 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Keene, 1943-1947 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Kel, 1940-1953 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Ker-Kih, 1942-1956 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Kilpatrick, 1939-1946 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Kin, 1940-1954 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Kir-Klu, 1943-1949 (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Kob-Koe, 1941-1947 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Kohlberg, 1947-1952, (6 Folders) (Box 72, Folder 11 to 15)
    - Kohlberg, 1945-1946, (2 Folders) (Box 73, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Kohn, 1944-1947 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Kohn, 1939-1943 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Kolatch, 1990-1993 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Kol-Kon, 1940-1947 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Kor-Kri, 1941-1953 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Kri-Kwe, 1942-1953 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Lab-Lam, 1939-1952 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Landauer, 1944-1954 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Lander, 1947-1948 (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Lang, 1949-1957 (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - Lan-Las, 1940-1948 (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - Lat-Laz, 1941-1948 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Led-Len, 1940-1948 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Len-Lev, 1939-1949 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Levitas, 1946-1949 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Lewis, 1937-1950 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Lib-Liv, 1940-1948 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Loc-Low, 1946-1949 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Luce, 1945-1946 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Lundberg, 1942-1949, (2 Folders) (Box 74, Folder 9 to 10)
    - Lyons, 1938-1947 (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Mac-Mal, 1939-1945 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Man, 1945 (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - Mar-May, 1941-1946 (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - McC, 1942-1951 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - McDowell, 1952-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 75, Folder 2 to 3)
    - McF-McN, 1938-1945 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Mea-Min, 1939-1945 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Moa-Mor, 1938-1957 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Morrison, 1936-1945 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Morton, 1944 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Mumford, 1940-1946, (2 Folders) (Box 75, Folder 9 to 10)
    - Mun, 1942-1945 (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Mur-Mye, 1943-1950 (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - Naf-Nik, 1939-1953 (Box 75, Folder 13)
    - Noble, 1947-1954, (2 Folders) (Box 76, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Nol-Ore, 1939-1954 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Pad-Par, 1940-1946 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Pat-Peg, 1938-1945 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Perlman, 1942-1945 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Pet-Pil, 1940-1951 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Pinson, 1942-1949 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - PM-Poo, 1942-1950 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Pope, 1942-1951 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Por-Pow, 1939-1950 (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Pra-Pri, 1943-1952 (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Pri-Pus, 1944-1946 (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Putnam, 1948-1950 (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - Rab-Raw, 1943-1948 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Rea-Rey, 1939-1954 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Rhe-Rii, 1943-1947 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Rod-Roh, 1939-1946 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Rom, 1939-1949 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Romualdi, 1942-1947 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Roosevelt, 1943-1947 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Root, 1945-1948 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Ror-Ros, 1938-1947 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Ros-Rua, 1945-1950 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Rubin, 1939-1949, (2 Folders) (Box 77, Folder 11 to 12)
    - Rug-Rus, 1943-1948 (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Russell, 1939-1945, (2 Folders) (Box 77, Folder 14 to 15)
    - Ryan, 1941-1944 (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - Ryskind, 1939-1947, (2 Folders) (Box 78, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Sac-San, 1939-1953 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - San-Sar, 1942-1957 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Sca-Sch, 1942-1948 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Scherman, 1943-1947 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Sch, 1939-1958 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Schnabel, 1947-1949 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Sch--Seg, 1939-1951 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Seligman, 1953-1957 (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Sen, 1939-1957 (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Senior, 1944-1957 (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Serge, 1943-1948 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Sev-Sha, 1941-1948 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - She-Sho, 1941-1957 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Shu-Sil, 1942-1956 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Sim-Sin, 1940-1950 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Ska-Sok, 1935-1950 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Sollman, 1938-1948 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Sol, 1941-1952 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Sor-Spi, 1939-1956 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Spi-Sta, 1946-1957 (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - Sta, 1943-1957 (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - Ste, 1947-1951, (2 Folders) (Box 79, Folder 12 to 13)
    - Ste-Sto, 1939-1948 (Box 79, Folder 14)
    - Storey, 1948-1952 (Box 79, Folder 15)
    - Sto-Stu, 1939-1957 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Sul-Sym, 1939-1948 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Tar-Tho, 1939-1954 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Tichenor, 1944-1946 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Thomassen, 1945-1948 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Tod--Tre, 1939-1948 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Uni-Val, 1934-1945 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Van Loon, 1938-1945 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Vei-Vil, 1940-1945 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Vishniak, 1943-1946 (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Voo-Voy, 1941-1946 (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Wag-War, 1942-1952 (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Was-Way, 1941-1957 (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - WCFM, 1949-1952 (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - Web-Wel, 1942-1956 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Whe-Whi, 1940-1946 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Wil, 1943-1954 (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Wil-Wis, 1940-1951 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Wit, 1942-1950 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Wittmer, 1949-1952 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Woh-Wol, 1941-1946 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Woll, 1941-1950 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Woo-Wun, 1941-1946 (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Yut-Zol, 1943-1947 (Box 81, Folder 10)
  - Subseries II. 2: Correspondence, 1939-1958
    The remainder of Levitas’ letters, these files arrived as a group and their integrity has been maintained. Researchers looking for a comprehensive collection of correspondents’ interactions with the magazine should make sure to check this subseries as well as subseries 1.
    - A--General, 1948-1952 (Aaron, Abrams, Adams, Adams, Aldanov, Alperstein, Allen, Allen, Anderson, Alter, Angoff, America--2 Folders) (Box 82, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Alexander, Robert J., 1948-1953 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Alexander, Mark (Laquer, W.), 1947-1952 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Alsop, Joseph, 1946-1951 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - American Jewish Committee, 1945-1951 (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Americans for Democratic Action, 1948-1952 (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Andler, Pierre, 1945-1948 (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Andras, Andrew, 1943-1952 (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - Angadi, Ayana Deva, 1948-1952 (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - Angell, Norman, 1942-1953 (Box 82, Folder 11)
    - Anti-Defamation League, 1949-1951 (Box 82, Folder 12)
    - Archer-Axtelle, 1941-1953 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Ayers, Clarence, 1945-1952 (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Ballou, Richard, 1950-1952 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Barbash, Jack, 1948-1953 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Bardin-Barron’s, 1948-1952 (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Barzun, Jacques, 1950-1953 (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Beacon Press, 1951-1952 (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Beall, Jack, 1947-1951 (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - Beck, Lewis, 1950-1951 (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Beichman, Arnold, 1948-1952 (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - Bell, Daniel, 1946-1950, (2 Folders) (Box 83, Folder 11 to 12)
    - Berger, Sam, 1950-1952 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Bernays, Edward L., 1947-1953 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Bernstein, David, 1947-1952 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Bess, Demaree, 1946-1952 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Biddle, Francis, 1950-1952 (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Bisbee, Eleanor, 1947-1951 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Bloom, Solomon, 1948-1952 (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Bondy, Francois, 1949-1953 (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Braunthal-Buber-Neumann, 1949-1952 (Box 84, Folder 9)
    - Brown, Irving, 1947-1953 (Box 84, Folder 10)
    - Burnham, James, 1950-1951 (Box 84, Folder 11)
    - C--General, 1942-1953 (Carlin, Carliner, Carman, Carr, Carr-Gregg, Catholic Digest, Catholic Mind, Cherne, Childs, Chipman, Canham, Cizevsky, Clark, Clarkson, Collier, Commanger, Commentary, Common Sense, Conant, Coolidge, Cook, Coste, Craibe--3 Folders) (Box 84, Folder 12 to 14)
    - Carey, James B., 1942-1948 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Catlin, George and Brittain, Vera, 1947-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 85, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Chamberlin, William Henry, I, 1950-1953, (2 Folders) (Box 85, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Cork, James, 1948-1950 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Coser, Lewis, 1948-1952 (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Counts, George, 1939-1951 (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Culbertson, Ely, 1944-1950 (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - D--General, 1946-1953 (Dallas, Davidow, Dewhurst, Dobriansky, Dorizas, Drinan, Duckett, Dupee) (Box 85, Folder 10)
    - Dallin, David J., 1950-1952 (Box 85, Folder 11)
    - David, Henry, 1948-1952 (Box 85, Folder 12)
    - DeVegh, I., 1947-1950 (Box 85, Folder 13)
    - E--General, 1946-1953 (Ebon, Elliott, Engel, Erlich, Ernst, Estabrook) (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Eastman, Max, 1945-1950 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Emmet, Christopher, 1946-1950 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Epstein, Julius, 1947-1952 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Everybody’s Digest, 1951-1952 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - F--General, 1944-1952 (Fiedler, Finer, Finletter, Firt, Fischer, Fischer, Foot, Frank) (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Fagin, Bryllion, 1946-1950 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Farrell, James T., 1949-1951 (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - Fineberg, S. Andhil, 1947-1949 (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - Finnegan, Les, 1945-1951 (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - Fischer, Alfred Joachim, 1949-1953 (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - Fischer, George, 1946-1951 (Box 86, Folder 12)
    - Fries, Horace S., 1946-1951 (Box 86, Folder 13)
    - Fry, Varian, 1951-1952 (Box 86, Folder 14)
    - G--General, 1946-1951 (Gafen, Gibson, Gitlow, Givens, Glicksberg, Gliksman, Goffen, Goldman, Goodwin, Granger, Grant, Gurian) (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Gardner, Martin, 1949-1951 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Gedye, G.E.R., 1947-1952 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - George, David G., 1946-1950 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Gilbert, Rodney, 1948-1951 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Golden, Clinton S., 1948-1950 (Box 87, Folder 6)